Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Albums (Album File) circa 1800-circa 1980 (bulk 1860-1920) PR 2
New-York Historical Society
- [Cartes-de-visite album], [1867-187-] (Offsite-box 4, Volume 52)
  Cartes-de-visite made in many different locations, including Rome, Paris, New York, London, Naples and others; primarily portraits of women, also includes children, group portraits and men, including Mohammed Achemed[?], Alexandria, Egypt, 1873. See also Album #151, 392.
- [Family album: Ledlie], [1860-1869] (Offsite-box 4, Volume 53)
  Family portraits, each sitter identified, several families (related) represented including Ledlie, Herr, Sheffield, Brown and others, photos by Brady and others.
- Julia A. Harper, [1860-1879] (Offsite-box 4, Volume 54)
  "Julia A. Harper" embossed in gold on leather binding; signed by Julia Harper and James Harper on front fly leaf; family portraits, cartes-de-visite, tintypes; some sitters identified: Browne family. See also #197, 198; related to Harper Family Mss. Collection.
- [Albums of photographs of American and British celebrities and others], [1860-1879] (Offsite-box 4, Volume 55.1)
- [Albums of photographs of American and British celebrities and others], [1860-1879] (Offsite-box 4, Volume 55.2)
  From the Library of G. Creighton Webb (1853-1948). Gen. Scott and other Civil War officers, Washington Irving, Lord and Lady Russell, Lady Ellismere, Lord and Lady Clarendon, members of Parliaments, clergy, and others, some identified, many not; includes photographers from Europe and South America as well as the U.S. See four other Webb Family albums.
- [Album: cartes-de-visite; Steward family, others and Civil War Officers], [1860-1869] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 56)
  Includes Campbell Steward in the uniform of the Knickerbocker Grays; John Steward Jr. in uniform, other children including girl with hoop, girl with flag and boy with drum and large hat.
- [Unidentified family album with many images of bicycling and sailing], [1900] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 57)
  Family pictures including group portraits; people, including children, with dogs and puppies; men and women bicycling; sailing pictures showing yachts under sail, and group portraits of people on board a sailboat; people on horseback, cattle; an large ornamental gate (Mt. Auburn Cemetery in Boston?) a lighthouse; some of the pictures have had the woman pictured scratched out; possibly related to Album #76, 77.
- [Album of photographs of ceremonies for the unveiling of a monument marking the site of Fort Washington], 1901 (Offsite-box 5, Volume 58)
  Program of the event; views of Holyrood Church, including interior; Bennett estate: Lodge and gate, house, garden; "Minutemen" in Continental Army uniforms and others, including marching band; ceremonies, including Borough President Guggenheimer responding on behalf of the city; the saluting battery, "Regulars"; speakers tent; views of the fort showing earthworks and bastion.
- [Album containing tintypes and cartes-de-visite], [1860-1889] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 58.1)
  Album with tintypes and cartes-de-visite of mostly unidentified people, including a group portrait of men in top hats, and a carte-de-visite that appears to have been copied from a daguerreotype; photographers include Sarony and others; one view inscribed from C.P. Bergen.
- [Album of photographs of a tour of Civil War Battlefields and other historic sites], 1923, 1928 (Offsite-box 5, Volume 59)
  "School friends" on trip: Wm. Chatfield, Wm. Grady, Louis W. Marks, Eugene Nifenecker, Claude Leland, and Hazen Chatfield, many of whom are educators; group at Ft. McHenry, Baltimore, 1923; group starting out; with Col. Proctor at Fredericksburg; Lawrence Washington Farm; Chancellorsville; Germania Ford; Spotteswood Farm; Spottsylvania; Jefferson's home, Monticello; Cedar Mt. Battlefield; Aldie; Point of Rocks bridge; B&O canal and R.R.; site of Washington's Crossing of the Delaware; Valley Forge; Brandywine; views include monuments.
- [Photographs by Capt. [Edwin Willard] Deming at Standing Rock Reservation and other western locations], [1895] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 60.1)
- [Photographs by Capt. [Edwin Willard] Deming at Standing Rock Reservation and other western locations], [1895] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 60.2)
  Images at Standing Rock reservations, some posed, possibly for use as sources for illustrations by Deming; views, possibly of Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show; views in the S.W. showing adobe buildings and ceremonial dancing.
- [Carte-de-visite photographs of twelve non-commissioned officers and privates of the 6th Company, Seventh Regiment, National Guard, State of New York Called into service of the United States and mustered in at Baltimore, May 25, 1862] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 61)
  Civil War portraits.
- [Carte-de-visite portraits of literary, scientific, entertainment and political figures], [1860-1899] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 62)
- [Hill Family album], [1865] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 63)
  Cartes-de-visite of family members.
- Carrie H. Park, [1860-1889] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 64)
  Portraits of Carrie Park and other Park family members, friends or relatives of the Parks; one item signed and date 1884, most views earlier. See also #65.
- Caro[lyn] Doremus Park's photos of Foreign Monarchs, undated (Offsite-box 6, Volume 65)
  Foreign royalty and political figures. See also #64.
- [Album of photographs of unidentified family, ca. 1920s-1930s], [1920-1939] (Offsite-box 6, Volume 66)
  Snapshots of people on board a ship, at the beach, including woman holding up fish on a line; man laying stone and brick patio in back of a brownstone, and views with dogs.
- [Schermerhorn family album], undated (Offsite-box 6, Volume 67)
  Cartes-de-visite, tintypes; also includes view of Lincoln's bier in a funeral procession.
- Portraits of relatives, notables and professional associates of Tom Thumb, the Stratton, Bumpus and Warren families from the collection of his widow, the Countess Magri (M. Lavinia Magri, 1841-1919), undated (Offsite-box 6, Volume 68)
- Portraits of relatives, notables and professional associates of Tom Thumb ... from the collection of his widow, the Countess Magri, [1869-1872] (Offsite-box 6, Volume 69)
  Includes World Tour, 1869-1872.
- Portraits of relatives, notables and professional associates of Tom Thumb ... from the collection of his widow, the Countess Magri, undated (Offsite-box 6, Volume 70)
- Portraits of relatives, notables and professional associates of Tom Thumb ... from the collection of his widow, the Countess Magri, [1869-1872] (Offsite-box 6, Volume 71)
- Portraits of relatives, notables and professional associates of Tom Thumb ... from the collection of his widow, the Countess Magri, undated (Offsite-box 6, Volume 72)
- Portraits of relatives, notables and professional associates of Tom Thumb ... from the collection of his widow, the Countess Magri, undated (Offsite-box 6, Volume 73)
- [Album of photographs of the voyage of an Australian troop ship from Sydney to Alexandria during World War I], [1916] (Offsite-box 6, Volume 74)
  Images of ships in harbors, on board the transport including the guns, exercising horses, church services, recreation on board, nurses, Commander Cayley; the Suez Canal, Port Said, and disembarking at Alexandria.
- [Album of photographs by William and Silvanus Webber], 1898 Mar.-1899 Oct. (Offsite-box 7, Volume 75)
  Mt. Morris Park, including band stand in the snow; Fifth Avenue from Mt. Morris park; Grant's Tomb; waterfront views including the Battery, Brooklyn Bridge, Park Avenue Bridge, Belden Point on City Island, Fort Wendel in the Harlem River, Sailors' Home (or Shipbuilder's home) Sedgewick Ave. from the river, tugboat in Spuyten Duyvil Creek; Polo Grounds from 155th St. Viaduct; High Bridge; Streets, including Mt. Morris Ave., 7th Ave., Jerome Ave.; Durandoes; elevated train at 110th; man getting out of paddy wagon, near waiting ferry or steamboat, titled "Ten Days"; street views in Sing Sing (Ossining), including train station; Bronx Park; train siding in Fort Lee; Sawyer Memorial church, East 127th street; Skating at Lake Crotona; man in buggy, 7th Ave.; street in Mt. Vernon; looking out from Portree, Isle of Skye, with sailboats in the distance.
- [Family album, unidentified], 1907-1910 (Offsite-box 7, Volume 76)
  View in Boston and vicinity, including beaches, lighthouses, the Public Gardens; many images labeled "N.S." [Nova Scotia?]; also includes pictures of a small dog, and of children and other family members, and African American woman named Liza; Boston dentist in his office. See also #57, 77.
- [Family album: Maine and Massachusetts], [1905-1909] (Offsite-box 7, Volume 77)
  Beach scenes, seascapes; houses; cows in pasture; Boston dentist in office and with his dog; sports scenes, including hockey and baseball. See also #57, 76.
- Amherst College Real Estate, 1911 Nov. (Offsite-box 7, Volume 78)
  Images include college buildings, houses and farmland.
- [E.B. Child albums Vol. 1], [1890-1900] (Offsite-box 7, Volume 79.1)
  Snapshots, ca. 1890s-1900; girl, man with bicycles, including view pretending to be hurt, same man, performing in front of sheet hanging up on wall, man in park, women in park.
- [E.B. Child albums Vol. 2], [1890-1900] (Offsite-box 7, Volume 79.2)
  Patterned buckram cover: same man as in other small volume performing various roles.
- [E.B. Child albums Vol. 3], [1890-1900] (Offsite-box 7, Volume 79.3)
  Homes and street views, women, including elderly lady with cats, and women in front of ice cream parlor with dog, children, Christmas tree with doll on chair; man in cluttered workspace measuring chemicals, camera on the shelf; man posing behind frame. See also album #80, 81,101, 154.
- [Album of 5x7 photographs], 1905 (Offsite-box 7, Volume 80)
  Photographs of men with boilers, and with surveying tools; European-American man and woman in kimonos, having tea, posing with fan; Japanese woman in traditional dress; two elderly women and a boy; one of the men with the boiler is identified as F.T. Howe. See also album #79, 81, 101, 154, 274.
- Bi-centennial celebration of the building of Manor Hall, Yonkers, October 18, 1882 / photographed by H.S. Wyer (Offsite-box 7, Volume 81)
  Copy of the painting of Mary Philipse; Manor Hall; room occupied by Washington during visit; loan exhibition of portraits and relics, including coverlet, long gun, spinning wheel, Chilkat blanket and other items; military procession on S. Broadway; trades parade on Main Street; mass meeting at Manor Hall; U.S.S. Kearsarge on the Hudson River off Yonkers, including deck view of crew; U.S. Monitor Nantucket, including deck view; view of Yonkers from the Nantucket; Old St. John's Church. See also album #79, 80,101, 154, 274.
- [Livingston Family album], undated (Offsite-box 7, Volume 82)
  Inscribed "Cornelia Livingston, 1861" and "Mrs. Carroll Livingston, the compliments of the original."
- Lt. E. S. Northrup [Civil War portraits], [1860-1869] (Offsite-box 7, Volume 83)
  Portraits of soldiers and officers, a camp scene, a battlefield, other sites; portraits of celebrities; sentimental pictures.
- [Album of photographs of military encampments and parades and family photographs], 1911 (Offsite-box 7, Volume 84)
  Views of parade and encampment in Van Cortland Park, May 13, 1911, including Capt. O'Ryan and the 1st Battery; Col. Dyer and 12th Regiment; Governor Dix on horseback reviewing troops; views from May 30th, [Memorial Day?] including Cpt. Appleton and 7th Regiment; Col. Conley, 69th Regiment; group of sailors and navy officers; John A. Dix Post; Duryea's Zouaves; 71st Regiment; men in kilts; 17th Battery on march from State Camp, July 15, 1911, Ossining; in camp, Philips Manor; Brewester cottage, Hartsdale, including views of house, and butterflies on marigolds, chickens, cow and calf, unidentified people; Rye Beach, 1911; International Motor Boat Races, Huntington, Long Island, including views of racers, spectator's boats; Catskill Aqueduct near Briarcliff; couple in garden; man changing tire on his car.
- [Album of photographs of Rogers and Derby family members], undated (Offsite-box 8, Volume 85)
  Cabinet cards and photographs of paintings and miniatures of the Derby, Rogers and Coffin family. See also album #12, 315.
- Artists' Aid Society Annual Outings, [1892-1900] (Offsite-box 8, Volume 86)
- [Album of photographs of M. Asarow, family and associates], [1930-1959] (Offsite-box 8, Volume 87)
  Snapshots of Asarow and others including views in a garden, at the beach, in Italy and Switzerland; theatrical views, commercial portraits; man with movie camera.
- [Gilford family album], [1899] (Offsite-box 8, Volume 88)
  E. Gilford family of White Plains, including view of home, horses, chickens, oxen; family members; blizzard in Philadelphia, 1899, Bartram Park, Philadelphia Peace Jubilee; views at Rye Beach, on Broadway, on W. 75th Street; views on the East River and the North (Hudson) River.
- [Fowler [?] Family Album], [1920-1929] (Offsite-box 8, Volume 89)
  Note laid in: Robert Ludlow Fowler; Katherine Angela Seargeant Fowler, Katonah, N.Y., Fishers Island.; snapshots of children, portraits and group portraits, with pets, on tricycle, playing games; also includes view of house and garden. See also Albums 303-307.
- [Family album: Estes Family (?)], [1914] (Offsite-box 8, Volume 90)
  Primarily views of upstate NY, including the Au Sable River and Lakes and vicinity, including cabin; Alice Estes and brother; a small chapel named All Souls, including interiors; early automobiles; St. Hubert Family; horses; a balloon; children wrapped in American flag; war bulletins outside Herald building, New York City. See also #91.
- [Family album: Estes Family (?)], [1920-1929]; Travel photos: early automobiles; upstate NY?; the steamer Kingston; beach and boating scenes, ferries; child in airplane hanger, early seaplane; portraits and interiors. See also #90. (Offsite-box 8, Volume 91)
- [Snapshot album of the home of Capt. Charles Hawley and Alice McConkie Brantingham at Larchmont], undated (Offsite-box 8, Volume 92)
  House and garden of the Charles Hawley Brantingham home in Larchmont, including views on the porch and in the garden, some with pet dog and cat; looking out at Long Island Sound at ships and boats.
- [Snapshots of parks, rivers, celebrations], [1899] (Offsite-box 8, Volume 93)
  Bronx Park, [Prospect?] Park, including bridges and sheep on the long meadow, boats and ships on the Hudson River, on deck on a battleship, Revolutionary War monuments, interior view, portrait of a little girl, boy fishing, High Bridge, mill building, Civil War monument in a cemetery; Tom Paine Monument, house on 142nd decorated with bunting and stars, fountain, Dewey arch from grandstand, photographers in the foreground, Cooper Union, man with bicycle, waterfalls.
- [Kane Family album], [1900] (Offsite-box 8, Volume 94)
  U.S. Battleships: Texas, New York, Machias, including view on deck; views in Bermuda: Hamilton Hotel, homes, St. George's Church, Victoria park, harbor, dry-dock, landscapes including roads, palm trees, etc.; quarry, Hawkins Island, P.O.W camp, April 1902; "Miss Prune" painting; a little girl, Betty Howland.
- [Album of family photographs], [1901] (Offsite-box 9, Volume 95)
  Construction of the Williamsburg Bridge; snow scenes (Brooklyn?) in streets and backyards, including boy with snow shovel; views on the [Hudson], including an Iron Steamboat co. ship, and views on board the ship; group aboard at sailboat; interior views of a parlor, and soda fountain, and an office, showing wrapped packages piled on the floor and on shelves; men at roll-top desks, possibly at Frank Tousey, Publishers, which is shown in an exterior view; a desk in the corner of a room, with drafting instruments, small plaster sculpts and other items, including one view with man sitting at desk; man with large camera; Park Row from City Hall Park; Herald Square; a beach scene.
- William Sulzer. [Alaska and Washington views], 1924 (Offsite-box 9, Volume 96)
  Clippings documenting Sulzer's 1924 trip to Alaska interspersed with views (by Guy Llewellyn) of mountaineering on Mount Rainier in Washington State, including interior views of ice caves, glaciers, and men on a rock cairn; men and a biplane; postcards from along the route of the Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railroad; views from the Copper River area of Alaska. See also Albums #117, 118, 162.
- [Martin Family Album], [1901] (Offsite-box 9, Volume 97)
  Views of a trip to Buffalo to the Pan-American Exposition in Buffalo, including views along the way at Niagara Falls, interior and night views at the expo, a lion cub on the midway; views on Lake Titus, Adirondacks, including boating, hiking and swimming scenes, cottages, including interiors, and porches; hotels; man with ox team and wagon of hay; early automobile with sign: Syracuse to White Mountains; log school house including interior; Paul C. Martin and his camera.
- [Horace B. Clark Album], 1899-1901 (Offsite-box 9, Volume 98)
  Views of New York, including the Dewey Naval Parade up the Hudson and parade on Fifth Avenue; views of New York City including street scenes, views from roof tops, Battery Park; Bowling Green; City Hall; Union Square; Central Park; Grand Army Plaza, Brooklyn; Brooklyn Bridge and the east River; ships on the North River; Bronx Park and Zoo; elevated railroads; Williamsburg Bridge; Blackwell's Island; Governor's Island; Riverdale.
- Album presented to Major M.S. Euen by Co. C., P.P., [1860-1869] (Offsite-box 9, Volume 99)
  [156th Regiment, N.Y.S.V.], portraits of officers and soldiers including an African American man, and including several portraits of women, including African American woman.
- [John Quincy Adams Ward albums], [1888-1889] (Offsite-box 10, Volume 100.1)
  Inscribed to Ward from [A?] W.D.,[Anthony W. Dimock?], 1889.
- [John Quincy Adams Ward albums], [1888-1889] (Offsite-box 10, Volume 100.2)
  Has literary quotes and song lyrics as captions for the photographs.
- [John Quincy Adams Ward albums], [1888-1889] (Offsite-box 10, Volume 100.3)
  Inscribed in the same hand as 100.1 from "the perpetrator." Related album at the Albany Institute of History and Art. Views of camping, boating and fishing in Peekamoose, N.Y., Pennsylvania, New Brunswick and Florida; includes images of Ward, and of persons named Dudley, Mulford, Oscar Yale, Whiton, and Mrs. Lewis; includes shark and tarpon fishing; includes swimming scenes, a dog jumping out of a boat, men poling boats up river.
- [Family album from Portland, Maine], [1890] (Offsite-box 10, Volume 101)
  Family groups and individuals, many times with a dog or a cat, sometimes with a horse; man with hoe; street scene; baseball team; industrial buildings and waterfall; boy with banjo; chickens, ducks; waterfront; men working on house; Longfellow statue, with flags overhead; building decorated with bunting; railroad locomotive; man with horse, and wagon painted on the side: "W.H. Frank. Deering."; man with wheelbarrow, and men with boy in wheelbarrow; a church. See also album #79-81, 149, 154, 274.
- [European views: Cannes, Dijon, Paris, Hamburg, Saint Moritz, Val Bregoglia, Lake Como, Lake Lugano, Lecco], 1905 April - October (Offsite-box 10, Volume 102)
  One of at least 12 albums (this one labeled "XII"). Views of royalty, others on yachts, at hotels, etc., and of scenery in France, Switzerland and Italy. See also album # 103, 104.
- [Travel photographs in Egypt], 1893 (Offsite-box 10, Volume 103)
  One of at least 12 albums (this one labeled "VIII"); travel photographs: Egypt: Cairo, up the Nile to the second Cataract and down to Karnak; laid in: Francis Edward Brantingham, photographs made during travels with his mother and Emmeline Smith Hawley his aunt." See also album #102, 104.
- [Travel photographs in Egypt], 1893-1905 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 104)
  Brantingham, Francis Edward. One of at least 12 albums (this one labeled "IX"); travel photographs: Karnak, Thebes, Cairo, Alexandria, Jerusalem, Bethlehem, Bethany, Syria, Asia Minor, Greek Archipelago, Smyrna, Athens Patras, Olympia, Corfu, Miscellaneous (including Switzerland, 1901, 1905; Monte Carlo, 1900). See also album #102, 103.
- Howitt's etchings: new edition containing 50 designs, [1812] (Offsite-box 11, Volume 106)
  Howitt, Samuel, 1765?-1822, etcher. Etchings of animals, including cattle, sheep, chickens, hogs, horses, dogs, lions, boars, deer.
- Europe, February 3 to June 9th, 1913 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 105)
  Robinson, Pauline, compiler. Views on board ships, including the" Auguste Victoria," and views in Madeira, Spain, including La Alhambra, Granada; Algeria; the Riviera, including views of touring cars; Sicily; Italy including Rome, Florence, Venice and Lake Como; Malta; Greece; Syria, including views at train station and market; Jerusalem; Egypt; group portraits, views in gardens, at ruins and other sites, ship-board scenes.
- [Album of landscapes, ships and boats], [1900] (Offsite-box 11, Volume 107)
  Landscapes including streets and rural roads, a small river [Bronx?] including view of African American man on horseback with other horses standing in the river and winter scenes; Grant's Tomb including night illumination; battleships, row boat and moored sailboat on the Hudson; dock scene with passenger ship; sailboat passing swiftly under full sail; porch of house with decorative woodwork; portrait of a dog.
- [Album of photographs of military camps and Indian agencies in Arizona and New Mexico], [1890-1899] (Offsite-box 11, Volume 108)
  Ft. Bayard, N.M., San Carlos, A.T., Fort Apache, Ariz., Ft. Stanton, N.M.; woman and baby; Lt. Walton; dog sitting up "on guard" at top of stairs; Col. Bliss and officers at Ft. Bayard; group portraits (commercial photographer) of Apache, Mojave and Indians, including women, children, scouts, some in traditional costume; cactus and soapweed; general views of Ft. Apache; San Carlos Agency: general view, Saturday issue, officer's quarters, surgeon's quarters, including interior with Apache woman and child; Battalion of the 24th infantry; dead wildcat at Ft. Stanton; Col. Z.B. Bliss at the Hotel Del Coronado; group of men (Apache?) with guns including Al-che-zay.
- Sesquicentennial celebration, Brown Brothers Harriman & Co., Seattle Washington - Sun Valley, Idaho, September 15-19, 1968 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 109)
  Published by Arendy Photos. Album covered embossed with name of Mr. And Mrs. Juan T. Trippe; color photographs; Seattle: the Space Needle, buses in front of the Olympic Hotel, tour of Boeing Aircraft plant, party in a tent, Union Pacific Railroad; views enroute from Seattle to Sun Valley including views on board train, and at stations, and views of scenery in eastern Oregon and Idaho; Sun Valley: the Opera House, group portraits, band in bandstand, dinner dance.
- Chaplains and Surgeons, asst. to surgeon G. Grant, Medical director of Madison, Indiana General Hospital, 1863-1865 (Offsite-box 11, Volume 110)
  Most signed beneath image by sitter.
- [Alexander Orr autograph album], [1860-1861] (Offsite-box 11, Volume 111)
  Portraits, most cut into small ovals and mounted, some inscribed by the sitter, some labeled later; includes Orr family portraits, and portraits of Gov. H. Morgan, D. Murray, G. McNaughton, Mrs. Abram Pierson, Anna Johnson, Mary Seak, Anna Stevenson, A. H. Dean, Jennie McNaughton, William Poleman, Rev. D. Rodgers, Isabel Lockwood, C. Staats, Stephen Douglas, John O. Cole, Rev. Dr. Seeley, Mr. and Mrs. Andrew White, Mr. and Mrs. James Moore, W. R. Bush, Jr., Rev. Dr. Magoon, E. Waterbury, Erastus P. Rice, D.P. Austin, Alex Roberts, Christian Sheldon, McClure, Edward McC. Davis, Anna H. Miller, Mrs. Taylor, Mrs. Diamond; many of the sitters associated with Albany. See also album #287.